Ryan Nolan

Number: 07801570610
Email: ryannolan1990@hotmail.com
Location: Barnoldswick, Lancashire
Github: github.com/RyanNolan1
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/Ryan-Nolan1

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have been a production manager for a workwear company for the past nine years and whilst the job provided me with financial security I found the repetition of doing the same thing every day very unfulfilling and tedious. I decided that I wanted to pursue a career that was more inline with my personality and found software development to be the natural choice as I am a creative person who enjoys problem solving and I have an educational background in IT.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: Javascript

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, React

Back End: SQL, Express **Testing:** Node.js, Jest

EXPERIENCE

Northcoders | Coding Bootcamp | October 2022 - January 2023

Manchester

A 13 week full-stack web / software development bootcamp

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, SQL, Express, Node.is and Jest
- Best practices, paired programming and test driven development
- Version control using GitHub and project management using Trello

Front end project - Fuel Price Checker:

https://github.com/RyanNolan1/fuel-price-checker

Front end project - FC-NC-Games:

https://github.com/RyanNolan1/FE-NC-Games

Back end project - BE-NC-Games:

https://github.com/RyanNolan1/BE-NC-Games

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

Jaybee Supplies Ltd | Production Manager | 2013 - 2022

Earby, Lancashire

- · Managing a team of four to ensure orders are delivered on time and to a high standard
- Interviewing and training of new production operatives to work in the factory
- Planning production daily to establish priorities and issues with orders
- Ordering materials to used in production

- Inputting embroidery logos on to the system and sending them to clients for approval
- Using Wilcom embroidery software to edit stitched logos
- Using CorelDraw to create and edit vector images
- Using the embroidery and heat press machines to decorate garments
- Checking stock quantities received from suppliers are correct
- Dispatching orders on the system to be sent to the client
- Delivery orders directly to the client in the company van

EDUCATION

New Media Design and Technology Foundation Degree: Pass | 2009 - 2011

University of Central Lancashire, Burnley

- Adobe Photoshop
- · Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Dreamweaver
- · Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Flash
- HTML, CSS and Javascript
- · 3D Modelling Software

A Level | 2004 - 2008

Nelson and Colne College, Nelson

- Graphics C
- ICT C

GCSE | 1998 - 2003

Ss John Fisher and Thomas More High School, Colne

- · Mathematics B
- Engineering C
- ICT C
- · Science C
- English Literature C
- English Language C
- Religious Education C

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Hiking, Mountain Biking and PC Gaming